

Senior Software Developer seeking roles as BI Developer



Current Designation: Senior Software Developer Total Experience: 7 Year(s) 0 Month(s)

Current Company: Ecobaised Technologies Private Ltd. Notice Period: 15 Days or less

Current Location: Bengaluru / Bangalore Highest Degree: B.Tech/B.E. [Computers]
Pref. Location: Bengaluru / Bangalore

Functional Area: IT Software - Application Programming /

Maintenance

Role: Software Developer

Industry: IT-Software/Software Services

Marital Status: Married

Key Skills: Power Bi, SSIS, MS SQL Server

Verified: Phone Number | Email - id

Last Active: 21-Jan-21 Last Modified: 21-Jan-21

Summary

6+ Years of Professional experience in IT Industry and 6+ years' experience in SQL server 2008/2012/2016, and 2+ years of relevant experience on BI (SSIS), 2 years of experience in Power BI.

- · Worked on Power BI Reports & Dashboards with SQL Server.
- · Experience in Data Conversion and Data Migration using SSIS services across different sources like SQL, Excel and flat files.
- · Good experience in deploying the projects in Production (Live) Environment.

To accomplish challenging roles where I can effectively employ my knowledge and skills making valuable contributions for business excellence, while growing as a Software Professional

Work Experience

Ecobaised Technologies Private Ltd. as Senior Software Developer

Sep 2015 to Till Date

Title : eAudIT (Period : Oct 2018 - August 2019)

Client : KPMG, UK

Role : Developing & Supporting
Environment : SSIS, SQL SERVER, Power BI

Description:

KPMG methodology is designed to exceed national and international standards and all our professionals throughout our member firms around the world are guided by the same approach to methodology, processes and documentation. All audit staff undergo frequent and regular training to help ensure their knowledge is as current as possible. Another strength of our audit approach is the use of technology to enable and streamline audit testing. KPMG offers the audit industry's most technologically empowered audit through the eAudiT application. eAudIT provides fully customizable electronic workflows offer industry-leading audit design flexibility for our firm's engagements. eAudIT brings the power of KPMG's collective wisdom, industry knowledge, and technical skills to our firm's clients on every audit engagement using advanced and secure technology tools.

Responsibilities

- Collect, summarize, analyse data and to provide reports for departments in decision making.
- * Identifying the Dimension tables & Measure tables to be used in the project.
- * Get the data from On-Premises data bases & On-Premises data sources to perform visualizations using Power BI Desktop

- * Implemented DAX (Data Analysis Expressions) functions for calculated columns and measures
- * Responsible for creating and changing the visualizations in Power BI reports and dashboards on client requests.
- * Created charts like Lines, Pies, Bar, Scatter, Area, Tree map, Map, Filled map, Gauge, Funnel, Single Card, Multi row card, Slicer etc. and customized visualization
- * Experience on publishing Power BI reports on dashboards in Power BI server.
- * Created reports and dashboards and shared among multiple users in the organization.
- Created On-Premises Gateway to refresh the data sources/ created a live connection.
- * Schedule refresh by connecting through gateway.
- * Created content packs that package up a dashboard, report, and dataset to send to my colleagues.

Description:

Insurance Processing System is designed for the people and their needs on the insurance segment. The company provides different insurance coverage with different plans and insured term values. It suits all the mid-level insurance companies across the continent. The objective of the project is to provide an efficient environment to reduce the time and the manpower and give companies centralized software solution by giving them a customized application. Company using this application can consistently and efficiently monitor the transactions done by the agents of every insured individual. This is need of the hour in the banking industry for global revolution.

Responsibilities

- * Understanding the business needs and provide the solutions accordingly
- * Development of packages according to the ETL specifications for the staging area data load & warehouse data load using Integration Services
- * Used Control Flow Tasks like For Each Loop Container, Sequential Container, Execute Task, Email Task, and Data Flow Task based on the required scenario.
- * Creation of package using required transformations like Derived Column, Conditional Split, Aggregate, Lookup, Sort, Data Conversion and Script Task to different levels of loading.
- * Creation of log providers, event handlers to SSIS packages as per requirements.
- * Implemented Configurations and Deployment to SSIS Packages.
- * Developing Procedures, Functions as per business requirement.
- * Extensively worked in Deploying and Scheduling the Reports.
- * Generated the reports weekly and monthly wise as per the client requirements

VSM Software Pvt Ltd., as Software Engineer

May 2011 to Oct 2012

VSM has delivered a wide range of business applications and end to end solutions. One of the major focus area is Sales Force Effectiveness software solution for Pharmaceutical industry which enables field sales force and managers, brand leaders and compliance teams to work in total coordination. And also provide banking services to support the requirements of core banking and applications.

Responsibilities

- * Involved in day to day data analysis and development activities in vb .net for clients.
- * Able to write stored procedure, complex SQL queries for data extraction and analysis.
- VBA Macro Programming based on client requirements providing required level of support.
- * ERP functional consultant for the client using Syspro ERP System.

Carborundum Universal Ltd as System Engineer

Apr 2009 to Apr 2010

Murugappa Group is one of India's leading multi-divisional business conglomerates. Carborundum Universal Ltd., one of its major units, pioneers in the manufacture of Coated Abrasives and Bonded Abrasives in India in addition to the manufacture of Super Refractories, Electro Minerals, Industrial Ceramics and Ceramic Fibres. Besides manufacturing, marketing and distribution CUMI also involved in a diversified works like mining, power generation and TOT agreements with various organizations.

Responsibilities

- * Trouble shooting errors and implementation in various modules such as Inventory, Sales, Shipping, Quality Control, Maintenance and Purchase in Ramco ERP system using VB.net.
- * Handled multiple work locations at Bangalore, Hosur, Chennai, Aurangabad, Delhi and Ludhiana.
- * Creation of Stored Procedures in SQL SERVER 2000.
- * Creation of Reports with the help of Crystal Report 9.0.
- * Creation of front end screens using Ramco Development Kit.
- * Tracking and study of the modules, user requirements and deployment to fulfil the functional bugs.

Education

UG: B.Tech/B.E. (Computers) from Sahrdaya College Of Engg. & Tech., Calicut University in 2007

Other Qualifications/Certifications/Programs:

Diploma (Computer Engineering)

ANIIT

IT Skills

Skill Name	Version Last Used Experience
C, C++, Java, J2EE,	
VB.Net ,ASP.Net, XML,	
RDBMS, SDLC, SQL, Oracle ,Oozie	
MapReduce, Pig, Hive, HBase, Spark	

Languages Known

Language	Proficiency	Read	Write	Speak
English				
Hindi				
german				
Malayalam				
Kannada				

Affirmative Action

Physically Challenged: No

Work Authorization

Job Type: Permanent

Employment Status: Full time